ADRIAN BALDERAS

Mechatronics Engineer • (899) 230-7372 • adaniel.balderas@gmail.com

SKILLS

Microsoft Excel

Excellent

Failure Analysis

Advanced

Problem Solving

Intermediate

Programing Logic

Advanced

LANGUAGES

English

Intermediate

Spanish

Native

COURSES

- Green Belt Certification
- · Yellow Belt Workshop

PROFILE

Mechatronics engineer with 8 years of experience in electrical failure analysis, 3 years in customer service (Variance) developing macros for inventory control and following tickets of out-system units. I am an eager a person who is willing to learn, expand my knowledges and exploit my creativity to resolve new problems.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Failure Analysis Technician at Ametek Lamb (ISC Division)

March 2018 - May 2021

Analysis and repair of line defects of instrumentation control products, electronic schematics interpretation, abilities with soldering iron and electronic measurement instruments.

- Technical support in 3 production areas.
- · Electrical analysis and repairs to more 10 product families.
- · Auxiliary support to maintenance area.

Engineering Lecture at Universidad Tamaulipeca

September 2017 - January 2018

Teaching subjects of mechanical drawing (AutoCAD), Introduction to engineering and algebra in the faculty of engineering.

Customer Service Technician at Microsoft/iQor

June 2015 - July 2017

Logistic process of Customer Service flow, Service Center for customer of Microsoft products, following of issues in the receipt process.

- Developed an Excel macro that print a barcode to control the inventory.
- Developed an Excel macro to automate inventory reports.
- Implemented a webpage of answers templates to minimize response time to service center.
- · Leadership on work area.

Diagnostic Technician at Jabil/iQor

May 2011 - June 2015

Electronic diagnostic of TV receiver motherboards, oscilloscope and multimeter management.



EDUCATION

Mechatronics Engineer, Universidad Técnologica de Tamaulipas Norte

September 2012 - May 2014

Mechatronics TSU, Universidad Técnologica de Tamaulipas Norte

September 2009 - May 2011